foreign
[Music]
I was visiting my grandmother this
weekend on the coast where it is much
warmer than back home I had the
opportunity to visit a botanical garden
and Greenhouse it was such an enchanting
experience and made me ache to my very
bones for springtime
thank you
I enjoyed my trip to civilization as
this Garden was near Seattle an enormous
City on the corner of my state I have to
admit I'm always surprised having gotten
used to rural living at the sheer amount
of advertisements and businesses that
are on every corner it is surprising to
be bombarded with Billboards and malls
and supermarkets full of a hundred
different choices for cereal and lotion
and everything in between
the amount of choices is always a tad
overwhelming but I do like to use my
trips into the city as a chance to stock
up on some bulk items for a lower price
living in a town with one small grocery
store means the local prices can be very
high so we try to purchase in bulk when
we travel
[Music]
foreign
this year I wish to continue being
careful when I'm thinking about buying
unnecessary items taking time to wonder
where it comes from if I really need it
or if there's an alternative I can make
it home
but I think that simply resisting
purchasing isn't as helpful or effective
as going within and reflecting on your
own philosophy in regards to what items
nurture you and what simply adds to
clutter or purchase to suppress emotions
that are asking to be heard
foreign
to my inner emotions the more I realize
that nothing will resolve them unless I
stop listen and nurture myself with
nothing else but quality time with my
soul
I cannot speak for everyone but
consistently distracting myself with how
I feel only makes the feelings more
prominent or keeps me disconnected from
my true self
it's as if my mind and body are asking
me to pause to look around and celebrate
that right at this moment I am safe and
I don't need anything in order to grow
[Music]
thank you
as an artist and Etsy shop owner I love
to support other creators and small
business owners and share their work
with the world as I know it can be
difficult to make a living in that field
I enjoy mindfully spending when I wish
to purchase something useful beautiful
or enriching instead of impulsively
picking up a bunch of clothes I may only
wear a couple times
it helps me live in alignment with what
I believe even though I still falter
often
[Music]
laughs
I've made several videos on my love of
thrifted old things from vintage
knickknacks to centuries-old books this
year however I wish to keep an eye out
for friends and relatives who I know
will enjoy one of these treasures and
share with them a piece of what I love
when I first started selling art I sold
primarily small prints that fit into
envelopes because I liked the idea that
the purchase would be shared with other
people
not only must we share necessary
resources for survival with others but I
think we also need to share beautiful
things we have crafted it matters in
ways that are harder to explain but
valid nonetheless I think of that quote
from Dead Poets Society that there are
things we need in order to sustain life
and then there are things that may not
be needed but make life worth living
for me that is Art in all its forms in a
world that did not relish it would be a
sorry Place indeed
[Music]
laughs
foreign
goal I have that will certainly impact
things this year is going through my box
of some old clothes that I've been
meaning to mend for a very long time and
I have not because I know there are a
lot of pieces in there I will use if I
can just adjust them to my size or mend
some tears so that is what I'm working
on today and I plan to do that so that I
don't need to make any new clothes
purchases this year I remember when I
was younger and close was quite
important to me because I was quite
insecure about my height and I really
felt like certain types of clothes would
make me you know appear better even
though I realized later that it really
is the clothes that make you feel better
that make you more confident and less
insecure as in comfortable clothes
clothes that make you feel good in your
own skin and don't make you feel
self-conscious even though I was never a
big spender with clothing I still think
back to all the pieces of clothes I
purchased for the wrong reasons that I
probably uh only wore maybe once and did
not make me feel good usually they were
secondhand items anyway because I was
very frugally minded in University
but still it felt like a waste now I
focus on practicality and things feeling
comfortable and if you are thinking that
Prairie dresses and skirts are not
practical then you should know that in
my world they very much are cottage
style dresses will always be practical
in paola's Fairyland so don't worry
about that another goal I have that will
impact my budget is that I do want to
visit family members my siblings now
live far away and I really do want to be
able to see them and so I am keeping
that in mind this year because even
though I'm not the best traveler over
long distances I really do feel it is
important to see them and still have
them in my life because phone calls and
zoom calls are just not quite the same
so yes my goal is to simplify finances
as much as possible even though I know
that is not always easy to do
this is not a strict regimen it's not
like I'm not going to allow myself to
get a treat
or do something just for fun now and
then I I really don't believe in being
super strict about these things
throughout University I always felt very
very stressed about money and especially
right after I did not find it easy to
get a well-paying job with a literature
degree I struggled for quite a while to
figure out what I wanted to do and I
even started working at a preschool
which was slightly unrelated I had this
constant awareness of how hard it was to
be independent and I stressed about it
for so many years and now that I have my
little Etsy shop and this Channel and I
am married to my husband who works as a
surveyor we have finally entered this
era of feeling safe and feeling stable
and secure and we are able to entertain
the idea of being able to start a family
and that is really exciting and I am so
grateful every day for that opportunity
if you are at a point maybe in
University maybe you're just starting
out you know your career or you're in a
different situation altogether and you
are feeling stressed about finances I
will share with you something that
really helped me throughout the years
taking a moment to while you're
breathing deeply think about all the
things you are grateful for and the fact
that hopefully at this very moment in
time you are safe I would take always a
moment to be grateful for my breathing
my physical self I would go through all
the things in my life that made me happy
and brought me joy and made me feel
grateful for being here
and I would allow all that feeling of
abundance all the things that I did have
instead of focusing on what I didn't
have fill up my heart and even though it
didn't resolve the issue I had regarding
finances it helped put things into
perspective and I would was able to come
back to that problem that I needed to
solve with a calmer mind and think a
little bit more patiently about who I
could go to for help or what I could do
to resolve the situation everything is
impermanent you might be really stressed
right now but you hopefully will get to
a place where you can feel much better
and more stable and things change all
the time if there's only one thing I've
taken from life so far is that few
things stay the same you evolve and
change and whatever challenge you're
facing take comfort in knowing that a
day from now a week from now maybe years
from now you will be in a completely
different place and be a completely
different person and you will get
through this so at the end of every
month you will find me going through my
purchases and being Mindful and looking
back at the last several weeks and
thinking about what I did when I what I
want to do differently in the future and
really considering my long-term goals as
well and really nurturing that inner
self that doesn't need to purchase
things in order to feel fulfilled we
really take heart and think about not
necessarily what we are buying but why
we are buying it and I found that it has
offered me some very deep fulfillment to
be more mindful about that I still worry
sometimes about the future and not
always knowing if I'll be in a place to
easily provide for my future children
and the people I love but Luke always
reminds me that we are safe right now we
are secure right now and we just need to
take deep breaths be generous and
support others and be involved in our
community and have faith that we will
find our way and we will receive back
the love that we give
if we ever are in need in any way last
but not least thank you everyone who has
supported this channel I would not be
able to make a living as an artist
without people that appreciate art I
just got disturbed by my lovely mother
she stopped by to walk my dog with me
and spend some time with me so I'm going
to go do that with her I'm sending all
of you my love have a beautiful and
wonderful week and I will see you very
very soon
goodbye
[Music]